Okay, little VidCon update: I officially have a room,
time, and date for my workshop.
My workshop will be on Friday, July 24th,
from 3:30pm to 4:30pm at Room 205.
And the workshop is called Lights, Camera,
Caption.
Credit to my boyfriend for thinking of that.
[clap]
If you were planning on coming to my closed
captioning workshop, that’s all the info
that you need to know. Write it down and if
you haven’t registered for VidCon yet, go
do that.
Now that that is settled, I am now doing little
videos to help prep me for what I want to
talk about in my workshop.
Starting with this one.
So as you know, and if you haven’t known,
I’ve been e-mailing, tweeting, and sometimes
handwriting letters to a plethora of YouTubers
telling them and asking them that they need
to closed caption their videos.
Sometimes, I’ll leave a comment under their
video telling them or asking them to closed
caption their videos.
Like when Ashley Mardell announced her little
project, I asked her to closed caption her
video.
When Veronica made a video about skincare,
I asked her to closed caption her video because
these are important videos that have information.
Not just comedic videos.
And sometimes after I leave a comment under
a video, I get a comment from either the creator
themselves or the viewer, er, a viewer, telling
me that I should, or that there should be
a CC button between this and that on the video
and that should give me the captions.
As if I haven't tried that before already
before I left a comment.
but I don't get fussy with it, I just say
something like,
"Well, you know, I'm a Deaf vlogger that advocates
for better closed captioning or some closed
captioning, at all, on YouTube and there's
a big possibility I've already checked to
see if there's closed captioning before I
left this comment.
And even if I wasn't a vlogger, there's still
a chance I checked for the captioning before
I left this comment.
There's no closed captioning on this video,
I promise.”
And this is actually something that happened
recently, and the person replied with,
"I'm just trying to help, I thought this would
be better than nothing"
When somebody leaves me, or anybody else this
comment, and it's happened before from even
bigger YouTubers,
I think, if I try to help somebody I do try
to make sure and check my possible answers
a little bit before I actually insert my answer
and give it to them.
So, I check to make sure that I'm a little
bit right before I give it and if I'm not
sure, then I'll leave a note that says, "I'm
not 100% sure, so you know, maybe look it
up yourself as well."
So, I know that when so and so tells me, or
anybody else to click that button and it'll
just automatically give it to me, I know that
this person has not actually looked at the
stuff themselves.
And that’s when I say, “Automatic cRaptions
are not captions.”
Automatic closed "cRaptioning" is not closed
captioning, and that's when I just ask politely,
and I ask,
"Have you actually looked at these things
yourself?"
Because, if you had, you would know that it's
completely nonsensical and it won’t help
me at all.
"Well, I just thought it was better than nothing."
“Okay, but answer my question. Have you
actually tried it, yourself? Have you muted
the video? Just mute the video.
Read the automatic "cRaptions" and let me
know if you understand what this video’s
about.”
And then I never got a reply. In fact, I think
the person actually deleted the entire comment
thread which is a little disappointing because
I'm not trying to argue. I just want to - instead
of me just saying,
"Those aren't captions."
I am trying to get people to look at them.
Pretend you’re me, mute the video or lower
the volume significantly, and look at it and
you will see, you will have an actual experience
that tells you -
That’s not working.
Now, sometimes people will take screenshots
of the automatic cRaptions and post about
it and then they laugh at it and laugh at
how ridiculous it all sounds.
Sometimes, automatic cRaptions are really
funny. I’ll give that. They’re funny.
There’s nothing wrong with laughing at ridiculous
captions.
But instead of just giggling at the ridiculousness
of terrible automatic cRaptions, I’m thinking,
“Why don’t we just think about this a
little bit more and think about those who
need actual closed captioning and just think
about how this does not help.”
And just like I’m going to do in my workshop,
I’m going to show you some examples of automatic
cRaptions.
And I’m going to give you videos, or examples
from videos of people that are going to VidCon.
Featured creators just like me.
And that means I can show you almost every
single creator - at least one video per creator
- but then that would just make this way too
long.
Let’s start with the oh-so-popular Grace
[Helbig] who I think is a very nice person
and can be hilarious; however, her stuff is
not captioned.
Here’s an example from her “What’s Up
My Butt Challenge”.
“well I I’m here and I remembered me out
I am today”
“where playing a game that is based on a
challenge that exist on you to call but”
“what’s in my mouth challenge”
Now I know she’s done a What’s In My Mouth
Challenge video, I’m pretty sure, but if
somebody has not watched that video or doesn’t
know who Grace is, and “What’s Up My Butt
Challenge” was the first video somebody
saw, this makes no sense whatsoever.
And Grace not captioning her videos always
kind of makes me giggle. I find it a little
bit ironic -
Is that how you use this word in this situation?
Let me continue.
On page 71 in her book “The Art of Pretending
to Be A Grown Up,” and I’ve reviewed this
and I’ve mentioned it in that video -
When she was younger, she did a few internships
at MTV transcribing videos for My Super Sweet
16.
So she transcribed for an MTV show, why don’t
you - or find somebody to transcribe your
videos?
And when you look at the automatic cRaptions
on her video…
There’s a Tumblr that actually transcribes
every single video and the Tumblr person and
I have been trying to contact Grace on Twitter,
tried to find an e-mail just, you know, offering
to send these transcripts so all Grace needs
to do is upload them.
The work’s already done. She just needs
to upload them because we don’t know the
login to her account.
So that’s gonna take some work.
And then we have Smosh who is a duo on YouTube
that has 20 million subscribers. That’s
all I know.
Btut Caption Action 2 has been trying to get
me to do a video, a separate video, on Smosh
because Smosh is premiering a movie at VidCon
the day before my workshop, unfortunately,
and.. 20 million subscribers and you don’t
caption your videos.
So from “The Murder Party”
“woman so the mail on the mailman okay male
woman just sounds weird hear anyone”
[MOUTHS: WHAT THE FUCK?]
>From “Worst Sex Ever: Behind the Scenes”
“i think is in doubt about a future together
because the fans are fickle ass”
1 - that’s not how you compliment your fans.
2 - I don’t know what that’s actually
trying to say. I don’t know what the audio
says, but “because the fans are fickle ass”
does not sound like something I would want
to say or want my video to say.
So while I don’t know if I can get Smosh
to caption their movie before VidCon, uhm…
Hopefully, it -
Hopefully, with some work, I can get Smosh
to caption their videos eventually.
And then we have AmazingPhil “I Destroyed
My House”
“one second caveman for dinosaurs you can
make a bet”
That’s like the very first line in that
video and, uhm, I - I don’t understand.
And then I decided to mention this guy because
he has mentioned almost every time he does
a YouNow that the closed captioning on YouNow
- or, I’m sorry - the automatic closed cRaptioning
- on YouNow is completely nonsensical and
it’s awful
But this guy does not closed caption his videos
at all and that is Nathan aka TheThirdPew.
I am a big fan of Nathan.
I’ve been a fan of Nathan since the
Sam Pepper callout video.
And I think a lot of people would enjoy his
channel, but it’s not accessible.
Here’s an example.
With his newest video “Do YouTubers Have
Responsibility?”
“follow-up as long as a crazy today girl
is going be quite heated acre lot eyes even”
Nathan, I know you look at the automatic closed
cRaptioning on your YouNow. Can you please
look at it on your own videos?
This is why it’s so important for YouTubers
to caption their videos and while it can be
a tedious process depending on how long your
videos are -
I know. I did a 22 minute video that took
four days.
But if I, the Deaf vlogger, can do it, hearing
people, you can do it.
And if you don’t have times, there’s many,
many options.
If you’ve got the money, you can pay to
have them done for a very affordable price.
You can get volunteers on Amara to do it.
There’s a thing on some YouTube channels
that lets people contribute closed captioning.
Or you can just simply ask people to e-mail
transcripts which is what I’m doing for
people who are subtitling my videos into Spanish
or Portuguese or any other language that is
not English.
I mean, this time, I’m showing you the proof.
I’m showing you examples of this nonsensical
automatic closed cRaptioning.
If you mute these videos and then you watch
them with those on, you can’t understand
the videos.
Automatic cRaptions are not better than nothing.
They’re really not and that is proof.
Yes, it may get some words right. It may get
an entire sentence right, but when 95% of
the video makes no sense, they’re not better
than nothing.
So my plan now is, of course, to keep working
on my workshop and to do the workshop.
I’ve given you the info of when, where it
is. Friday, July 24th. 3:30-4:30pm at Room
205.
So come see me and…
Not only that, but I’m going to keep trying
to e-mail, tweet, uh I think I’m going to
try to handwrite a letter to every single
featured creator - even if I’ve already
done it -
It’s easy to delete an e-mail. It’s also
easy to throw away a letter, but you do have
to open up a handwritten letter and look at
it, so it’s a little harder to miss than
an e-mail.
Like I said in other videos related to my
workshop, if you’ve got ideas on what I
can talk about in my workshop, feel free to
leave ‘em in the comments.
I have a loose outline right now.
I’ve just got work to do.
So yeah, I will see you in my next video.
Bye.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community